Chandler! Chandler!
錢德！錢德
I saw what you were doing in the window!
錢德，我從窗戶看見了
I saw what you're doing to my sister! Get out here!
我看見你在對我妹做什麼了 你給我出來
Listen,we had a good run.
聽著，我們玩得很開心
What was it? Four,five months?
總共4個月？5個月？
That's more than most people have in a lifetime. Goodbye.
比很多人一輩子加起來都久 再見，保重，再見了
-What are you doing? -I am going on the lam.
你幹什麼？ 我要落跑
Come on,Chandler. I can handle Ross.
過來，我應付得了羅斯
Hold on!
等一下
Hey,Ross. What's up,bro?
羅斯老哥，你好嗎？
What the hell are you doing?
你幹了什麼好事？
What's going on?
發生什麼事了？
I think Ross knows about me and Monica.
我想… 羅斯發現我和摩妮卡的事了
Dude,he's right there.
他人就在那裡
I thought you were my best friend! This is my sister!
我以為你是我最好的朋友 這是我妹妹
My best friend and my sister! I cannot believe this!
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹 我真不敢相信
We're not just messing around. I love her.
我們不是玩玩而已，我愛她
I'm in love with her.
我愛著她
I'm so sorry that you had to find out this way.
抱歉讓你這樣發現
I'm sorry, but it's true. I love him too.
對不起，但是真的，我也愛他
My best friend and my sister!
我最要好的朋友和我妹妹
I cannot believe this!
我真不敢相信
You guys want to probably get some hugs in too. Big news!
你們也想抱抱吧？大消息喔
We've actually known for a while.
我們知道一陣子了
What? You guys knew?
什麼？你們知道？
You all knew and you didn't tell me?
你們都知道，卻沒告訴我？
We were worried about you. We didn't know how you were going to react.
我們很擔心你 不知道你會有什麼反應
You were worried about me?
你們擔心我？
You didn't know how I'd react?
不知道我會有什麼反應？
Okay. All right.
好吧
Let's clear out of here and let these lovebirds get back to business.
我們要不要清個場 讓這對小情人繼續辦事？
I'm just talking here. He's the one doing your sister.
我只是說說，上你妹妹的是他
The One With the Girl Who Hits Joey
本集播出：「情海生波」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
「中央咖啡館」
You know what I just realized?
你們猜我想到什麼
If you guys have kids
要是你們生了小孩…
We're having kids?
我們生小孩？
I call godfather!
教父是我的
You can't just call godfather.
哪能這樣用說的
Shouldn't her brother be godfather?
你不覺得應該由她哥哥當嗎？
Sure. If you cared enough to call it first.
當然，你有心就應該先喊
-You're a few steps ahead of us. -Big zero gravity moon steps.
你們想得太遠了 十萬八千里的遠
I just thought of the greatest wedding gift.
我剛想到一樣最棒的結婚禮物
I'll go in on that with you. I couldn't decide.
我跟你送，我什麼都想不到
Hey,Katie.
凱蒂
This is Katie.
各位，這是凱蒂
You ready to go?
可以走了嗎？
I'll run to the bathroom.
可以，我先上個廁所 往後走
Where's lunch?
我們午餐要吃什麼？
I was thinking Chinese food.
我想吃中國菜
I love Chinese!
我最愛吃中國菜了
How did you know I love Chinese?
你怎麼知道我愛吃中國菜？
She is so cute.
她真可愛，
You could fit her in your pocket.
可以塞進口袋裡
She could fit in that little pocket inside the pocket.
可以塞進口袋的小口袋裡
I don't know. I like her a lot, and she's really nice,but....
我不知道，我很喜歡她 她人很好，但是…
But what?
但是怎樣？
She keeps punching me.
她老愛打我
In the cute,little sweet way she just did?
用她剛才那種可愛的方式？
It's a lot harder than it looks.
力道比表面上大多了，好嗎？
She's hurting me.
她把我打痛了
I know what you need. You need a bodyguard.
我知道了，你需要保鏢
What is Ben doing after preschool?
羅斯，班下課之後有事嗎？
Joey is having a problem. A little girl is beating him up.
別這樣，喬伊有煩惱 他被個小女孩揍了
Joey,come here.
喬伊，過來
Honey,I know. This must be really difficult for you,and
我知道你一定非常難受…
I'm sorry,am I hurting you?
抱歉，我握痛你了嗎？
I brought you some housewarming gifts.
我帶了喬遷之禮來
Salt, so your life always has flavor.
鹽，讓你的生活有味
Bread, so you never go hungry.
麵包，讓你永不飢餓
And a scented candle for the bathroom.
浴室用香精蠟燭
Because,well,you know.
你知道的
Thanks. Thanks. And thanks,I guess.
謝謝，謝謝…再次感謝
Welcome. I'm Steve Cera, president of the tenants' committee.
歡迎你搬進來 我是史提夫沙拉，管委會主席
Ross Geller. And this is my friend Phoebe.
你好，我是羅斯蓋勒 這是我朋友菲比
Mr. President.
你好 主席先生
I came to talk to you about Howard.
我來跟你談霍華的事
He is the handyman who's retiring next week.
霍華？ 他是這裡的雜工，下星期退休
Everyone who lives here is kicking in $100 as a kind of a thank you.
這裡的住戶決定每人交1百元 感謝他多年來的辛勞
That's nice.
真有人情味
Yeah. So, do you want to give me a check?
是啊，所以你想開支票還是…
Not now. You can slip it under my door.
你不必現在給我 你可以塞進我家門口
No,it's not that.
不是那樣的
I just moved in.
我才剛搬來
Well,the guy's worked here for 25 years.
他在這裡工作了25年
Yes,but I've lived here for 25 minutes.
但我才搬進來25分鐘
Okay,I get it.
好，我懂了
Wait! Look, I'm sorry, it's just I've never even met Howard.
等等，我很抱歉 但我甚至沒見過霍華
I mean, I don't know Howard.
我不認識霍華
Howard's the handyman.
霍華是雜務工人
Yes,but to me,he's just "man."
但對我來說他只是個人
Okay. Fine. Whatever.
好，隨便
Welcome to the building.
歡迎你搬進來
Can you believe that guy?
真是有夠扯的
I really like his glasses.
是啊，我很喜歡他的眼鏡
So then President Steve told everyone I was a cheapskate...
史提夫主席逢人就說我吝嗇
...and now the whole building hates me.
現在整棟樓的人都討厭我
A little kid spit on my knee.
有小孩朝我的膝蓋吐口水
And told me to wipe it off with my $100 bill.
還叫我用百元大鈔去擦
You really should wipe it off with something.
你是該擦一下
You know what?
你們猜怎樣？
I'll throw a party. For everyone in the building.
我要辦一場派對 邀請整棟樓的人
And I'll sit them all down and explain that I am not a bad guy.
我要請他們坐下，告訴他們 我不是壞人
I am not a cheap guy. I'm just a guy...
不是吝嗇 我只是個...
...who stands up for what he believes in.
...堅持理念
A man with principles.
有原則的人
Sounds like a fun party.
聽起來真好玩
If you want them to like you, why don't you just pay the $100?
羅斯，如果你希望鄰居喜歡你 為什麼不付錢算了？
The party will cost you more.
辦一場派對更花錢
That doesn't matter!
那不重要
It's my principles! We're talking about my principles!
這是原則問題 重點是我的原則
I thought it was about your neighbors liking you.
好，我以為重點是討鄰居喜歡
They'll like me once they come to my awesome party.
等他們參加過我的派對 就會喜歡我了
I gotta get some nametags.
我得走了，我要去買名牌
And that crazy party animal will be your brother-in-law.
那個派對動物會是你的大舅子
Very funny. But don't say that to Monica.
真幽默，但別對著摩妮卡講
Don't put any ideas in her head.
別讓她有那些念頭
You do realize that those ideas are probably already in Monica's head?
錢德，你應該知道 她可能本來就有那種念頭了
Why?
為什麼？
Well,because she loves you and because you love her.
因為她愛你，你也愛她
Yeah,so? What's that supposed to mean?
那又怎樣呢？
Don't freak out! I'm telling you something you already know.
你不要被嚇到 我只是在講你知道的事
She left Richard because he didn't want to have babies.
她因理查不要小孩而跟他分手
And she is a woman. And she's almost 30. And, you know, it's Monica.
她是個女人，快30了 而且她是摩妮卡
I don't see it that way. I see two Monicas.
我不是那樣看的 我看到兩個摩妮卡
My friend who lives across the hall and wants a lot of babies.
朋友的摩妮卡住在對面 想生一大堆小孩
And the new Monica who I started to date.
另一個新的摩妮卡剛跟我交往
Now,who is to say what she wants?
誰曉得她想要什麼？
I'm right.
我說得沒錯
Am I right?
我說得沒錯吧？
Oh,absolutely.
當然
I'm completely different from Richard.
而且情況完全不同
He's an eye doctor, and I don't wear glasses.
理查是眼科醫生 我連眼鏡都沒戴
You're right.
你說得對
You're absolutely right. That makes everything different.
你說得一點也沒錯 情況確實完全不同
It's not different,is it?
一點也沒有不同對吧？
Not unless different means "the same."
除非不同等於一樣
You were so funny with that waiter. You're such a nut!
你跟那個服務生好逗喔 你真是個瘋子
You know,bread-stick fangs are always funny.
扮吸血鬼本來就好笑
No,you make them funny. You're the funny one!
是你讓它變好笑的，是你好笑
Look,Katie. Listen, we need to talk, okay?
凱蒂，我們得溝通一下
Look,I like you. I really do. I like you a lot.
我喜歡你，我真的很喜歡你
But sometimes when you playfully punch me like that...
但當你開玩笑打我
...it feels like I'm being hit with a very tiny but a very real bat!
感覺就像被一根很小 但很結實的球棒打到
Like I could hurt you.
我哪能把你打痛
Are you making fun of my size?
你在取笑我的身材嗎？
Don't make fun of me because of my size!
不要取笑我的身材
Isn't this great?
這種感覺真好
Couldn't you just stay like this forever?
真想永遠這樣
Couldn't you just stay here forever?
錢德？你想不想永遠這樣？
Yeah, here, somewhere else. You know,wherever.
這樣，那樣，哪樣都可以
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
I'm cool.
我很好
Casual.
很隨性
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Just hanging out. Having fun with the girl that I'm seeing casually.
只是隨便混混玩玩 跟你隨性的交往
Man,I knew it! I knew you'd do this.
我就知道，我就知道你會這樣
What?
怎樣？
Get all freaked out because everybody was joking about marriage!
被大家討論和開玩笑的事嚇到
Well,you do want all that stuff,right?
你的確想要那些事吧？
You know what I want?
你知道我想要什麼？
Yes! You want babies! You have baby fever!
沒錯，你想要小孩 你有孩子狂
I do not have baby fever!
我才沒有孩子狂
You're obsessed with babies and marriage...
拜託，你超迷戀小孩和婚姻
...and everything that's related to babies and marriage.
和一切跟小孩和婚姻有關的事
Why don't we turn the heat down on this pressure cooker!
我有個提議 讓這個壓力鍋減壓一下吧
Have you lost your mind?
你瘋了嗎？
This isn't about me. This is about you and your weird commitment crap!
這不是我的問題 是你不敢做出承諾
I know you. I know the thoughts that you have in your head.
少來，我暸解你 我知道你腦袋裡在想什麼
You don't know everything.
你並非什麼都知道
Did you know I'm going out with Rachel tonight instead of you?
你知道我今晚要跟瑞秋出去嗎
And that the only baby here is you?
你知道最幼稚的是你嗎？
Did you know I can't even look at you now?
你知道我連看都不想看你嗎？
I did not know that.
那我倒是不知道
It'll be okay, right? She won't leave me. This is fixable.
不會有事吧？她不會離開我吧 這是可以解決的
-Yeah,sure. -Absolutely.
當然
By me?
我可以解決?
Unless you make some big gesture.
除非你有大動作
Big,though.
要非常大
The missus!
女主角來了
Gunther, can I get a coffee?
阿甘，我要一杯咖啡
To go.
外帶
I still don't want to talk to you.
我還不想跟你說話
Tell me how to make things right.
告訴我怎樣彌補
That's what we do.
什麼？ 我們都這樣
I mess up,you tell me how to fix it and I do.
我做錯事 你教我怎麼補救，我補救完
And then you think I'm cute again.
你又覺得我很可愛
I'm really tired of being your relationship tutor.
我不想再當你的愛情指導了
Figure this out for yourself.
這次你得自己想，好嗎？
If you're afraid of a real relationship...
如果你懶得好好經營感情
...then don't be in one.
就別談感情
（歡迎）
（羅斯）
（蓋勒博士）
Howard! Howard! Howard!
霍華、霍華…
菲比？菲比
Hi,Ross!
羅斯
What are you doing here?
你在幹什麼？
I thought this was your party, and it's a party for Howard.
我以為這是你的派對 結果是替霍華辦的派對
He's the sweetest little man.
他真是個老可愛
See you,Phoebe. And thanks for chipping in.
菲比再見，謝謝你出錢
Oh,sure.
不客氣
You chipped in?
你出了錢？
Yeah,$100.
對，1百塊錢
I can't believe you gave him money.
你居然給他們錢
I thought you agreed it was unreasonable that they asked me for that money.
你不是也同意他們要我出錢 是很不合理的？
But they didn't ask me.
對，但他們沒有要我出
I'm just the exotic,generous stranger. That's always fun to be.
當性感大方的陌生人最好玩了
But you're making me look bad.
但你讓我很難看
No,I'm not! If anything, I'm making you look better.
誰說的，我是在幫你加分
They'll see you talking to me. I'm a hit.
他們會看見你在跟我說話 我又很紅
Hey,Phoebe!
菲比
Hey,Ross.
羅斯，
Maybe you two could switch apartments.
你們或許可以交換住處
Because Phoebe is more our kind of people.
菲比跟我們比較搭軋
Think about it.
你考慮一下
Okay,my bad.
是我不好
You look big.
哇，你看起來好壯
Thanks,I've been working out.
謝謝，最近有在練
Listen,is it obvious I'm wearing six sweaters?
看得出來我穿六件毛衣嗎？
Yeah. But it's not obvious why.
看得出來，但看不出來為什麼
I'm breaking up with Katie, so I put on some extra padding.
我要跟凱蒂分手 所以得多加幾層護墊
If she hits me when she is happy, can you imagine how hard she'll hit...
她平常高興就會打我 現在我要收回喬伊之愛
...when I take away the Joey love?
她豈不是打得更用力？
Oh,right. I forgot that you call it that.
我都忘記你的喬伊之愛了
Hey,cute jacket.
好可愛的外套
Thanks.
謝謝
-That's so sweet! -Ouch!
你真好
Did Joey tell you to say that? You guys are too much!
是喬伊要你叫的嗎？ 你們真是夠了
You know what? I gotta tell you...
你知道嗎？說真的
...I think you're the one that is too much.
我覺得你才夠了
Joey has the nicest friends.
喬伊的朋友真棒
And the nicest girlfriend.
女朋友更棒
You're so sweet!
你真好
你才好
She just kicked me.
喬伊，她踢我
Aren't you going to do something?
你不替我出頭嗎？
Do something or I'll walk out that door right now.
你最好替我出頭 否則我現在就走人
Are you going to?
你要不要？
不要
Phoebe?
菲比
That's what I'm saying.
我就是這個意思
Phoebe? Phoebe?
菲比？菲比
This is a disaster. Can't I please just go?
這真是人間地獄 我走了好不好？
I'm talking you up to people.
不行，我正在幫你說好話
Give it some time, relax. Get something to eat.
再等一下下 放輕鬆，拿東西吃，好嗎？
What did you tell them about me?
你跟他們說了什麼？
I told them about you and Emily. Trying to get some sympathy.
我說了你和艾蜜莉的事 好爭取同情心
But you came off as the bad guy.
但講一講你成了壞人
Yeah, I think I told it wrong.
我想我說的方式不對
We should talk about that because I don't understand what happened there.
我們應該先聊聊 我不太知道前因後果
This cake is really good!
這個蛋糕真好吃
Things are looking up.
看吧？情況已經在好轉了
Oh,my God! Someone cut Howard's cake!
天哪，有人切了霍華的蛋糕
Who would do a thing like that?
誰會做這種低級的事？
3B.
3B
You got your free food. You ruined everyone's fun.
你白吃白喝，掃了大家的興
Isn't it time you went home?
是不是該回家了？
Yeah, get out! Now!
沒錯，快滾
Go back to 3B,3B.
回3B去，3B
Everyone,calm down! I have something that I'd like to say.
大家安靜一下，我有話要說
Who here likes Ross?
這裡有誰喜歡羅斯？
Of course you don't like him.
你們當然不喜歡他
He didn't give you any money.
他不交錢
He raised his own hand when I asked, "Who likes Ross?"
我問有誰喜歡他，他自己舉手
And he's wearing two nametags.
他還貼兩個名牌
I'll be honest. When I first met Ross, I didn't like him at all.
老實說，剛開始我也不喜歡他
Once I got to know him, I saw that he is really sweet...
但暸解他之後 我就發現他很好...
...and caring and very generous.
...很大方
All I'm saying is,don't judge Ross before you get to know him.
請不要還不暸解他就論斷他
You know,I like all of you guys now. But when I first met you, you know?
我現在很喜歡你們 但是剛見面時
Kurt? I thought, abrasive drunk.
寇特，粗魯的酒鬼
Lola?
蘿拉
Mind-numbingly stupid.
笨得令人傻眼
You guys. Gold digger, cradle-robbing perv.
還有你們 淘金女，老牛吃嫩草的變態
So I think you all know what I mean.
你們懂我的意思吧
Obviously, I didn't think they would throw things.
我沒想到他們會扔東西
I thought if I kept insulting them you'd defend them.
我想說我一直羞辱他們 你就會跳出來幫他們
Then you'd look like the hero.
你就可以變成英雄 對喔
See,I did not get that.
太深奧了
Where's Monica? I need to talk to her, it's urgent.
摩妮卡呢？我有急事找她 她在嗎？
I'm Monica.
我就是摩妮卡
I need to talk to you. It's urgent.
我有急事要找你 好
I've been thinking...
我想了很多...
...about us. A lot of "us" thinking.
我們的事… 你和我的事
I guess there's only one way to do this.
我猜只有一個辦法
What are you doing?
你要幹什麼？
Don't do it.
摩妮卡… 拜託不要
Will you marry me?
你願意嫁給我嗎？
What a bad idea.
毀了 什麼餿主意
I can't not look at it.
我不敢看
Why are you doing this?
錢德，你為什麼要這樣？
I don't know.
我不知道
But I know I'm not afraid to do this.
但是我知道我不怕
I'm doing this because I'm sorry?
錢德 因為我很抱歉？
Do you think the best reason to get married is because you're sorry?
你真的覺得結婚的最好理由 是因為你很抱歉？
The best reason is pregnancy.
不，最好的理由是奉子成婚
Sorry is fourth,behind being ready and actually wanting to get married.
抱歉大約排第四 在準備好了跟真的想結婚後面
Will you be my wife?
你願意做我的妻子嗎？
I want you to take a minute and think about how ridiculous this sounds.
錢德，你先靜下來 想想這件事有多荒謬
I'm kind of wishing everyone wasn't here now.
我的確有點希望他們都不在
None of that came from me.
這些事都不是我扯出來的
I never said I wanted to have babies and get married!
我從來沒說現在就想結婚生子
I was really confused. Then I talked to these guys.
但我真的很亂 後來又跟他們談過
Who? Two divorces and Joey?
離婚兩次的人和喬伊？
She's right,you know?
她說得對
Yeah,but still, cheap shot!
但這種奚落算什麼？
You know when I said that I want you...
你知道嗎？
...to deal with relationship stuff all on your own?
我不是要你自己想該怎麼做?
You're not ready.
你還做不到這一點
I didn't think I was!
我也這麼認為
Oh,my God.
天哪
What would you have done if I had said yes?
要是我答應了呢？
I would've been happy because...
那我會很開心
...I would spend the rest of my life with the woman I love.
能跟心愛的人共度下半生
Or you would have seen a Chandler-shaped hole in that door.
又或者你會在那扇門上 看到我的人形洞
Will you pass that knife?
羅斯，請把刀子給我
No,I will not.
我才不要
You don't have to be mean about it.
你不必這麼凶吧
You're right. I'm sorry. Will you marry me?
你說得對，對不起 嫁給我好嗎？
I was going to ask you to marry me because I didn't say hello to you.
我正想向你求婚 因為我上星期忘了跟你打招呼
Or ask them to move in with you. But I'm not sure. Chandler?
那種情況應該只需要同居 但我也不確定，錢德？
How long is this going to go on?
好，我還要被笑多久？
I think the length of teasing...
那得看...
...is directly related to how insane you were. So a long time.
...你做的事有多扯 所以…會很久
This is fun!
真好玩
Remember that "we were on a break" thing?
記得「我們分手了」風波嗎？
I'm sorry. Will you marry me?
我很抱歉，嫁給我好嗎？
That's not funny.
不好笑 冷死了